# Bo Li, PhD student in machine learning

+45 60 69 82 98

() lyn1874

in Bo Li



https://BO-LI.NETLIFY.APP/

**ॐ** Available from Feb-2024



## **Summary**

I am a highly motivated, organised and dedicated Ph.D. (expected graduation in Jan 2024) with proven mathematical and coding skills, and a desire to learn more. I have 7+ years of experience using machine learning and deep learning for analysing various data types (medical images, Raman spectra, and videos). I am particular interested in analyzing real-world datasets and am eager to contribute my skills and knowledge to translate ideas more effectively, leveraging AI to tailor solutions for specific needs.

Skills:

Machine/Deep learning

Optimization

Federated learning

Uncertainty estimation

Anomaly detection PyTorch & Python Computer vision Spectroscopy analysis

Data visualization

# **Highlighted publications**

- B. Li\*, X. Jiang\*, M. N. Schmidt, T. S. Alstrøm, and S. U. Stich, "An improved analysis of per-sample and per-update clipping" in Proceedings of the International Conference on Learning Representations, ICLR 2024
- B. Li, M. N. Schmidt, T. S. Alstrøm, and S. U. Stich, "On the effectiveness of partial variance reduction in federated learning with heterogeneous data," in Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), Jun. 2023, https://arxiv.org/pdf/2212.02191.pdf
- B. Li, M. N. Schmidt, T. S. Alstrøm, "Raman Spectrum Matching with Contrastive Representation Learning" in Analyst, 2022, https://arxiv.org/abs/2202.12549
- 4 B. Li, S. Leroux, P. Simoens, "Decoupled appearance and motion learning for efficient anomaly detection in surveillance video," in Computer Vision and Image Understanding, vol. 210, p. 103 249, 2021 https://github.com/lyn1874/daml

#### **Awards**

2022 - 2023

Otto Mønsted Foundation funding

2016 - 2018

**Danish Innovation Scholarship under DABAI** 

#### **Skills**

Languages

Native Chinese, Proficient English, Basic Dutch (A1)

Coding

Python, PyTorch, R, Bash script, MATLAB, TensorFlow, Linux, GitHub, AWS, Plotly, Keras, Jupyter notebook, Basic level for React

# Work Experience

2019 - 2020 Belgium

- Researcher Ghent University Imec, Supervisor: Dr. Sam Leroux, Prof. Pieter Simones • Develop deep neural networks for detecting anomalies in surveillance videos under adverse
  - Develop distillation-learning based hardware-efficient framework for traffic counting [6]

## **Work Experience (continued)**

2018 – 2018 Denmark

- Research Assistant Technical University of Denmark, Supervisor: Prof. Tommy Alstrom
  - Explore uncertainty calibration within active learning for medical image segmentation
  - Develop region-based acquisition strategy to reduce labelling effort [9]

2018 – 2022 Denmark

- **▼ Teaching Assistant** Technical University of Denmark
  - Deep learning, 2021, 2023 Bayesian machine learning, 2022 Advanced data analysis, 2018

#### **Education**

2021 – 2024 Denmark PhD, Technical University of Denmark Applied Mathematics and Computer Science Topic: Federated Machine Learning for Raman spectra and Surface-Enhanced Raman spectra (SERS)

2022 – 2023 Germany Visiting PhD student, CISPA Helmholtz Center for Information Security
Topic: Accelerating the convergence of federated learning algorithms under high data heterogeneity

2016 – 2018 Denmark M.Sc., Technical University of Denmark Mathematical Modelling and Computation Thesis: Active multitask learning for object recognition in images using deep neural networks

2012 – 2016 China

**B.Sc., Jilin University** Financial Engineering
Thesis: The analysis of monetary factor in the context of capital market

# **All** publications

- **B. Li\***, X. Jiang\*, M. N. Schmidt, T. S. Alstrøm, and S. U. Stich, "An improved analysis of per-sample and per-update clipping," in *In Proceedings of the International Conference on Learning Representations, ICLR 2024,* 2024.
- **B. Li**, Y. Esfandiari, M. N. Schmidt, T. S. Alstrøm, and S. U. Stich, Synthetic data shuffling accelerates the convergence of federated learning under data heterogeneity, 2023. arXiv: 2306.13263 [cs.LG].
- **B. Li**, M. N. Schmidt, T. S. Alstrøm, and S. U. Stich, "On the effectiveness of partial variance reduction in federated learning with heterogeneous data," in *Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR)*, Jun. 2023, pp. 3964–3973.
- **B. Li**, G. Zappalá, E. Dumont, *et al.*, "Nitroaromatic explosives' detection and quantification using an attention-based transformer on surface-enhanced raman spectroscopy maps," *Analyst*, 2023. URL: http://dx.doi.org/10.1039/D3AN00446E.
- **B. Li**, M. N. Schmidt, and T. S. Alstrøm, "Raman spectrum matching with contrastive representation learning," *Analyst*, 2022. *O DOI:* 10.1039/D2AN00403H.
- **B. Li\***, S. Leroux\*, and P. Simoens, "Automated training of location-specific edge models for traffic counting," *Computers Electrical Engineering*, vol. 99, p. 107 763, 2022, ISSN: 0045-7906.
- **B. Li**\*, S. Leroux\*, and P. Simoens, "Multi-branch neural networks for video anomaly detection in adverse lighting and weather conditions," in *Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Winter Conference on Applications of Computer Vision (WACV)*, Jan. 2022, pp. 2358–2366.
- **B. Li**, S. Leroux, and P. Simoens, "Decoupled appearance and motion learning for efficient anomaly detection in surveillance video," *Computer Vision and Image Understanding*, vol. 210, p. 103 249, 2021, ISSN: 1077-3142.
- **9 B. Li** and T. Alstrøm, "On uncertainty estimation in active learning for image segmentation," in Proceedings of 2020 International Conference on Machine Learning: Workshop on Uncertainty and Robustness in Deep Learning, 2020.

## **Projects supervision**

- 1 2023, Project supervision: Explore the quality of the estimated uncertainty using federated learning
- 2 2023, Bachelor thesis: Explore representation learning in federated learning, Victor T. Olesen, and Rasmus S. Mikkelsen
- 3 2022, Project: Federated machine learning, Asger L. Schultz, Søren W. Holm, and Gustav L. Moesmand
- 4 2021, Project: *Unsupervised representation learning*, Till A. Aczel, Victor T. Olesen, Rasmus S. Mikkelsen, and David B. Ludvigsen
- 5 2021, Master thesis: Segmentation of cardiac structures based on MRI data using neural networks with analysis and evaluation of anatomical implausible segmentation errors (coding support), Katrine M. Ejlev and Michala Z. Blicher

### Referees

- 1. Associate Professor Tommy S. Alstrøm, Technical University of Denmark, ✓ tsal@dtu.dk
- 2. Associate Professor Mikkel N. Schmidt, Technical University of Denmark, Market Mrsc@dtu.dk